Ancient feudal Japan.
a land shrouded in mystery.
forbidden to foreigners.
A group of magical islands
home to witches and demons.
A nation of rival provinces
whose lords were ruled by a
shogun whose will is absolute.
Peace in the realm is
kept by the samurai.
master swordsmen
tasked with protecting their lord
and their province at all costs.
Should a samurai ever
lose or fail his master.
he suffers the greatest shame
in all Japanese society.
He becomes a ronin.
And yet. to know the
story of the 47 Ronin.
is to know the story of all Japan.
It began with a boy.
No one knew where he came from
or how he found his way to Ako.
Some said he was a changeling.
no better than a beast.
Many believed he'd been
raised by the Tengu.
the demons of the forest
who had taught him
their dark powers
and trained him in their
lethal arts of killing.
The evil he had fled had
left its mark upon him.
Oishi!
My Lord. it is a demon.
He's a child. just like you.
Help me pick him up. Oishi.
Lord Asano. of the province Ako.
saved him that day.
seeing something in the
boy that Oishi did not.
Lord Asano's daughter.
Mike. saw it too.
Mika's father allowed the
boy to live amongst them.
against the advice of his samurai.
Look.
What do you see?
A branch?
No.
It's a deer.
Oh.
It took this path.
You keep it. Kai.
The samurai believed his presence
would bring misfortune
to their land.
Mika only saw a gentle boy.
Although he lived as an outcast.
Kai was determined
to repay the love
he received from
Mike and her father.
whatever the cost.
Kai.
Well?
There is something wrong
with the creature.
It's up there on the rise. but
it will come down again to hunt.
It would be safer to set a
trap and wait for it here.
It's up on the rise. Lord Asano.
My Lord.
Kill it!
I would rather have been killed by
that beast than saved by a half-breed.
Yasuno!
Ako owes you a great debt. Yasuno.
We can finally welcome
the Shogun without fear.
For Ako!
Well done.
Get out.
Get out!
Does Lord Asano live?
Yes.
Mmm.
Hosting the Shogun's tournament
is a great honor for my father.
Everything must be perfect.
My Lady. Mika.
Lord Asano and the hunting
party have returned.
They killed the beast.
Father!
I was worried.
The hunt took longer than we hoped.
Yasuno showed great courage.
Is anyone badly hurt?
Who are you looking for?
Is everything prepared for
the Shogun's arrival?
Yes. Father.
I want all of Ako
to share in this honor
of hosting our great commander.
I have made special arrangements
for the visiting lords. as well.
I've ordered stands put
up all along the route.
Your mother would have been proud.
I was worried.
You always worry.
He so wants your approval.
Chikara has been training
every chance he gets.
My Lady. Kai has returned.
They told me you were hurt.
It's nothing. My Lady.
Your back.
Sit down.
Someone should have
seen to this before.
Thank you.
I saw the shame in Yasuno's eyes
when they were praising him.
Even when you try to help
them. they hate you.
Your father's samurai have always
treated me as well as can be expected.
And is that all you expect?
It's all I know.
It doesn't have to be. Kai.
This is no place for you. My Lady.
Are you sending me away?
Look at me and tell
me you don't love me.
I will always love you.
But you have your place
and I have mine.
Asano Takumi no Kami. ruler of Ako.
His Highness. Shogun Tokugawa.
lord of provinces and
master of all Japan
thanks you for your welcome.
Lord Asano.
my friend.
Ako is magnificent.
as always.
We anticipate with pleasure
tomorrows tournament.
Great Shogun Tokugawa Tsunayoshi...
and hope the entertainment
we have prepared
meets your august approval.
Father.
What are you doing in my home?
Last week at the hunt I saw a fox.
I didn't realize at the
time that it was a witch.
A witch?
I believe I saw the same
creature again tonight.
She was in human form among
the nobles' concubines.
My Lord.
They say only demons have the power
to see past a witch's disguise.
Are you a demon?
No.
Then I suggest you are simply
bewitched by a beautiful girl.
Lord Asano. may we
present Lord Kira Yoshinaka.
master of Nagato. from
the northern provinces.
Ako is as beautiful as I
remember. Lord Asano.
We are honored by your
visit. Lord Kira.
I look forward to the tournament.
I had no idea your concubine
was so lovely. Lord Asano.
She's my daughter.
Oh.
Forgive me. My Lady.
May I ask that your
daughter sit with us?
I should like to make
up for my rudeness.
Father. who is that?
My fighter.
I'm sure your father's champion
will be an even contest.
Yasuno.
Yasuno. Yasuno!
Yasuno!
What's wrong with him?
Witchcraft
Get your father.
There is no time.
If we have no fighter.
Ako will be disgraced.
Only a samurai can fight.
Enough.
Your fighter?
Champions. prepare for combat!
Bring them steel!
Stop!
You are not a samurai.
Kill it.
No!
Forgive me. My Lord.
The fault is mine.
Strip him of his armor.
Beat him.
Stop!
I'm sorry.
My Lord!
Not now!
Father. please!
Lord Asano's mind is unsettled.
It is time to take Ako.
It is what you hoped for. it
is what we have planned for.
What are you afraid of. My Lord?
Show me your courage.
Give me your heart.
After this. there
is no turning back.
You are bound to me. and I to you.
Rivers of blood
and mountains of corpses
will not stand in our way.
Nor the tears of widows.
Find your envy and hatred.
And I will give you all you desire.
Father.
Father!
Mika.
Help!
What is this?
Stand back!
My Lord!
Please!
Father!
Everyone. go back to your posts!
The law is clear.
You have struck an unarmed guest
and have shamed your home.
The penalty is death.
Because of your rank and the
service you have done Ako.
I will allow you to regain your
honor and the honor of your house
through seppuku.
death by your own hand.
so that you may show courage
and dignity in death
as you once showed in life.
The Shogun could have had
me hanged like a criminal.
Instead. he has allowed me
to take my life with honor.
You were bewitched. My Lord.
Your mind was poisoned.
If I accept my fate.
no one will question the
honor of our people
or punish them for my crime.
Promise me
you will protect Mika and
Ako from our enemies.
My Lord.
I am ready. Oishi.
And when I die.
I would be honored if you
would act as my second.
my friend.
Father!
Don't let them see you cry.
No.
We must have revenge.
Whatever the cost. it is our duty.
My Lord. what will you have us do?
If we fight now. we die.
And not just us.
Every farmer and villager
in Ako will be killed.
We have to think of them first.
Poison. My Lady.
It will end your pain.
We have not lost Ako yet.
Your Highness.
Lady Asano.
I am sorry for your father's death.
He accepted it with dignity.
Your Highness. as my
father's only child.
I ask that I may look after his
lands until such time as I marry.
I have already considered
this. My Lady.
So that there will be no
feud between your clans.
I decree that from this day.
they will be one.
Sealed by the marriage bond
between you and Lord Kira.
You are granted one year to mourn.
But you will remain a guest of
Lord Kira's until you are married.
Oishi.
You are now ronin.
Masterless samurai.
I forbid you to seek vengeance
for Lord Asano's death.
Lord Kira.
I leave Ako with you.
From this moment on. you are
banished from these lands.
Those who remain
will be hunted down
and executed.
You will never see him again.
My Lady. Take a last look.
I don't trust Oishi.
He no longer has the
protection of his rank.
Throw him in the pit.
Break his will.
Father!
Father.
Get away! Get away from me.
Chikara. help him up.
Where are my men?
They have all left Ako.
And Lady Asano?
Her time of mourning
is almost over.
Lord Kira took her to his castle
to begin preparing
for their wedding.
Chikara.
what of the half-breed?
Kira's men took him to the Dutch
island and sold him into slavery.
We need three horses.
Now.
Riku.
You must make the whole world
believe you've divorced me.
It is the only way to protect
you from what I have to do.
No one but you and I
can know that you are.
and will always be.
the joy of my life.
I am the wife of a samurai.
Whatever your duty is.
it is mine too.
Show them this
and tell them to meet me at
the black lake in a week.
Remember. the enemy
will be watching.
Hey. stranger.
What's your business here?
I'm looking for a half-breed.
Good luck. samurai!
Half-breed! Half-breed! Half-breed!
Kai!
It's Oishi.
It's me!
Kai! Lady Asano.
Mika.
She needs your help.
Half-breed! Half-breed! Half-breed!
Kai! Soon Kira will marry Mika.
We must stop him!
Are you with me?
Now!
Lady Asano is to be
married in a week.
What do you care?
When Kira took her away.
you were on your knees.
We would have all been killed.
You too.
What use are you to her dead?
What use am I to you?
Either follow me or go
back to what you were.
Don't turn your back on me. ronin.
Follow you for what?
Kira has 1.000 men
under his command.
He's also protected by witchcraft.
When I told you that.
you turned me away.
I was wrong.
I failed my lord.
I don't know who or what you are.
but I need your help.
Clothes.
I'll come with you.
but if you ever kneel before
Kira again. I'll take your head.
Where did you learn
to fight like that?
From demons.
My Lord. forgive me.
The half-breed has escaped
from the Dutch island.
They say a samurai helped him.
Oishi.
Find Oishi. I need him dead.
Yasuno. it's Oishi!
He's back!
Everyone. Oishi's back!
Oishi's back!
Father.
Well done. Chikara.
Today we may be ronin.
but now the time has come.
What I propose ends in death.
Even if we succeed.
we will be hanged as criminals
for defying the Shogun's orders.
I take a vow before you
that I will not rest
until justice is done.
will not sleep until our
master lies in peace.
and will not pray
unless it is to ask the
heavens' forgiveness
for sending Kira to hell!
There are only two ways in.
The main gate here
and this point beneath
the west wall.
Both are heavily guarded.
Our best chance is to strike when Kira
leaves the safety of his fortress.
He will travel to his ancestors'
shrine to offer prayers.
We don't know yet when he
will make the journey.
Isogai. you ride ahead
to his temple town
and see what you can find out.
Remember. even near holy sites
there are brothels and plenty of
loose-tongued officials who visit them.
Even if we know the route. we
will need more men for an ambush.
Then we'll get them.
You and Chuzaemon and Okuda
will gather as many of our
former samurai as you can
and meet us here at a farmhouse
Horibe has found for us.
Forgive me. sir. but how can we
succeed without good swords?
Take mine.
When we meet again. I'll
have more waiting for you.
The rest of us will go to Uetsu.
The finest swordmakers
in the land work there.
Why is the half-breed here?
I asked him to come.
We can't take him with us.
He's not a samurai.
None of us are samurai anymore.
Who are you?
We are farmers from Shimobe. sir.
We have come to buy tools.
This is Lord Kira's village now.
These are not farmer's hands.
Take the swords.
whatever you can salvage.
We'll need more.
Help him.
Eat. My Lady.
You think I care if you starve?
Soon my lord will be
ruler of all Japan
and you can take your life
like your father did.
You killed my father.
Weren't you the one
who broke his heart?
You betrayed him with your lust.
We can go to Hida.
They will give us weapons.
You will find nothing in Hida.
Kira's men will have taken
over this entire region.
There is another way.
You will find swords
in the Sea of Trees.
The Tengu Forest
That is just a myth.
I've seen them.
How do you know about
the Tengu Forest?
I was raised there
before I fled to Ako.
Those scars on your head.
Are they the ones who marked you?
Yes.
And taught you to fight?
To kill.
They have many strange
and magical ways
to protect themselves
and their beliefs.
They wanted to show me that this
life has nothing to offer but death.
They wanted me to be like
them and renounce the world.
I vowed never to use the
magical powers they taught me.
Although I was still a child. I knew
my place was among other men.
And do you think that these
Tengu would give us weapons?
They will test our will.
My wife just won't stop nagging me.
She wants me to find her the best
view of Lord Kim's procession.
Procession? What procession?
Nobody knows when Kira
will leave his fortress.
not even his own guards.
He will hurry back
before anyone is awake.
What is your name?
Yuki.
Where do you come from. Yuki?
You've come back.
Are we lost?
No. They know we're here.
What is that noise?
Ghosts.
Spirits of the old and infirm
who are left hereto die.
Unwanted children. too.
Only you.
I'm coming with you.
No.
Do as he says.
Stay here.
Whatever happens in there.
whatever you see.
don't draw your weapon.
Wait here.
How do we know the half-breed
hasn't led him into a trap?
Oishi trusts him.
Of course. he has no choice.
We need weapons.
If he doesn't come back soon.
I'm going after him.
So the terrified boy
returns as a man.
I have come for your help.
We are in need of swords.
Then take it.
These swords were forged to defend
us against the hatred of men.
Men who persecuted
us for our beliefs.
The same men who despise
you for being different.
And now you're here to help them.
They are good men.
Their cause is just.
Many come for our steel.
but none return.
You told him not to draw his sword.
If he does.
he and all his men will die.
Was it worth it? What you
found in the outside world?
The love of a woman
you can never have?
Yes.
Let me tell you of love. Kai.
The love of one night
that brought you into this world.
An English sailor
and a peasant girl.
Your loving mother abandoned
you to die in these woods.
A monster. a half-breed child.
Yet we found you.
accepted you. trained you.
We taught you many things.
But you fled
and you turned your
back on those gifts.
Gifts of death.
No matter what you do.
Mika will never be
yours in this life.
Then I will go to my death and
pray I find her in the next.
Sir?
What are you doing here?
I told you to stay.
No! Yasuno!
Draw your sword.
Save them.
Save your men!
No more talk.
Will you give me what I ask?
Take the blade. Kai.
If you can reach it before me.
Save your men. Help them.
Draw your sword. Oishi.
Save them.
Chikara!
A gift not forgotten.
You passed their test.
Your men are safe.
You've got your swords.
What's so special
about these swords?
What do they do?
It depends.
On what?
Who uses them.
What about a tall. strong.
brave man like me?
They cut.
I think mine is broken.
Your sword.
You keep it. Hazama.
I told you we'd bring others.
I have the information
you requested.
Lord Kira leaves for his
ancestors' shrine tonight.
Well done.
Come. Isogai. Gather the men.
Father.
I want to go with you.
No.
Horibe. stay with him.
I ride to my ancestors' shrine
to offer thanks for our wedding.
Is there anything you
wish me to pray for?
My Lord will not like my answer.
You may look down on me. My Lady.
but our children and their
children will be of one blood.
Take care. Hazama.
Sorry.
It's a trap! Go! Go!
Get back! Get back!
Get out!
Yasuno!
Oishi. help me!
It's Basho.
Hazama!
- No!
- Oishi!
It belonged to Oishi. My Lord.
Your half-breed is dead.
So are dozens of your father's men.
All killed
trying to save you.
Perhaps now you understand
the price of your love.
I promised my lord
I would not harm
a hair on your head.
But what you do to yourself
is not my concern.
Good night.
Kai.
I have a confession to make.
When I was a boy.
I used to wait in the
woods outside your hut.
and when you came out.
I'd throw stones at you.
then hide.
I knew it was you.
I could see your belly sticking
out from behind the trees.
I'm sorry. Kai.
You're a good man.
I should have acted the
day Lord Asano died.
Our anger should have
been sudden and swift.
Then even if we'd failed.
it would have been with honor.
You are samurai.
We still have swords and
the advantage of surprise.
Kira thinks we're ghosts.
We can use that.
turn it to our advantage.
He'll never expect us.
We can still do what we came for.
Eat.
- Your arm?
- Fine.
Go get your father.
Stay where you are!
What is this?
We are not some village troupe
to be held up by bandits.
Lord Kira himself has hired us
to perform at his wedding.
I have the letters and
passes to prove it.
There is no need.
We saw you perform in Ako.
You are Lord Asano's men.
We need your help.
Kai.
Forgive me for not thanking
you for defeating the beast
and saving my life.
A samurai does not take credit
for victories of others.
This belonged to Basho.
A samurai wears two swords.
When a crime goes unpunished.
the world is unbalanced.
When a wrong is unavenged.
the heavens look
down on us in shame.
We too must die for this circle
of vengeance to be closed.
We will leave this
record of our courage
so the world will know who
we were and what we did.
Tonight we will regain our honor
and avenge our lord.
None of us knows
how long he shall five
or when his time will come.
But soon all that will be
left of our brief lives
is the pride our children feel
when they speak our names.
Kai.
We end this now.
Now
we are 47.
What do you see?
The omens are good.
Soon you will travel far.
In every town and village.
people shall bow before you.
Halt!
Let them through.
Five minutes!
Lord Kira. we are proud
to present to you
our performance as a
gift for your wedding.
Don't hurt the princess!
Kai!
Get them!
Stay there!
I knew you'd come for me.
Nothing will ever keep
me away from you.
Nothing. half-breed?
Even death?
I know what you are.
You have no idea.
I'm not afraid of you.
You should be.
Come on.
Know now the depth
of my lord's courage.
In the name of Lord Asano of Ako!
For Lord Asano!
Chikara.
Rest now. My Lord.
You are avenged.
Oishi.
I gave you a command forbidding
you to take revenge.
Forgive me. Your Highness.
but a man may not live
under the same heaven
as the murderer of his lord.
All I ask is respect for my men.
They are brave. My Lord.
The bravest I know.
I beg you to let them die
with the dignity they deserve.
For the crime of disobedience.
you should all be executed
as common criminals.
But you and your men
followed the old ways of Bushido
to honor your lord
and to avenge treachery.
I see only samurai before me.
I grant you a samurai's death.
to be buried alongside your lord
with honor.
Thank you. Your Highness.
Lady Asano is like her father.
She will make Ako great again.
Yes.
I know.
My father told me
this world was only a
preparation for the next.
that all we can ask is that
we leave it having loved
and being loved.
I will search for you
through 1.000 worlds
and 10.000 lifetimes
until I find you.
I will wait for you in all of them.
Wait!
Chikara.
son of Oishi.
step out.
Oishi.
I will not deny our
country your bloodline.
Your son shall live
to serve Ako
as you and your samurai have done.
I will search for you
through 1.000 worlds
and 10.000 lifetimes
until I find you.
The memory of the 47 Ronin
who put duty and justice
before their fear of death
has lived down through
the centuries
as one of the greatest
examples of honor and loyalty
in Japanese culture.